

# Guilherme Morone Araujo

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/guimorone

**Gender:** Male **Date of birth:** 10/02/2001 **Nationality:** Brazilian

#### **ABOUT ME**

Originally from Rio but now based in Recife, I've had the privilege of growing up in two vibrant cities. My passions are as diverse as my background, ranging from an avid love for games and books to an insatiable curiosity for travel and technology. Furthermore, I am always eager to explore new opportunities and challenges that can help me grow both as a professional and as a person, fueled by my passion for learning and applying new technologies to solve real-world problems.

I have been working on Software Development since 2020, and I am used to developing Big Data applications that demand high efficiency, scalability, and low cost. All my projects demanded skills in web development, data engineering, CI/CD, Docker, GitHub Actions, and cloud computing, in order to deliver quality solutions to clients.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

[ 10/04/2024 – Current ]

## **Software Engineer**

Neurotech https://www.neurotech.com.br

City: Recife | Country: Brazil | Email address: guilherme.morone@neurotech.com.br | Name of unit or department: Hydra - Neurolake

Full-time job:

- In general, using skills in software, data engineering and backend development with Python, FastAPI, Terraform, Git, Airflow, Bash and cloud computing on AWS.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to achieve project goals.
- Ensure high-quality, scalable application development.
- Using Amazon Web Services such as Lambda, DynamoDB, EC2, Athena, S3 and more.

[ 03/09/2024 - 09/10/2024 ]

# **Full Stack Developer**

GPC Gestão https://gpcgestao.com.br

City: Recife | Country: Brazil

Freelancer:

• Built an admin website using React with TypeScript and Tailwind CSS.

[ 10/04/2024 - 31/05/2024 ]

# **Software Engineer**

Jalan https://jalan.com.br City: Recife | Country: Brazil

Full-time job:

· Worked as a Full Stack developer using Vue.js and Quasar along with Python and Lambda Functions (AWS).

[ 01/03/2024 - 31/03/2024 ]

#### **Mobile Engineer**

aca.so https://aca.so

City: Recife | Country: Brazil

Freelancer:

• Worked as a Mobile Engineer in a project (aca.so mobile app) using React Native.

[ 01/07/2023 – 28/12/2023 ] **Full Stack Developer** 

City: Recife | Country: Brazil

Freelancer:

- Website made with 3 more colleagues to an external customer.
- The main purpose is to identify bank check fields easily, so you do not have to type manually.
- The bank check OCR is based on our customer's API, we did not implement it, just the website.

- It also offers API Integration, history download and other features.
- Developed using React, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS and Django (Python).

#### [ 01/02/2022 - 28/12/2023 ] **Software Engineer**

Oncase https://www.oncase.com.br

City: Recife | Country: Brazil

Full-time job:

- Developed Big Data applications with a focus on high efficiency, scalability, and low cost.
- Developed frontend applications using React (JavaScript, TypeScript and HTML/CSS) and Redux.
- Implemented backend functionality using Python frameworks Flask and Django.
- · Implemented effective CI/CD pipelines for seamless integration and deployment through Docker and GitHub Actions.
- In general, utilized skills in web development (Django, React and HTML/CSS), data engineering, CI/CD, Docker, GitHub Actions, and cloud computing.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to achieve project goals.
- Enhanced customer relationships through the delivery of top-notch solutions.
- Ensured high-quality and scalable application development.
- Hosted applications on Google Cloud Platform using Cloud Run and Artifact Registry.
- · Utilized Amazon Web Services for hosting, leveraging services like Amplify, Route53, and Lambda.

#### [ 01/08/2022 - 31/10/2022 ] **Mobile Engineer**

**InSpace** https://inspace.tech City: Recife | Country: Brazil

Freelancer:

• Identification of objects (censored specificity) from a mobile camera for legal purposes.

#### [ 01/05/2020 - 30/12/2020 ]

# **Game Developer**

**Educandus** https://educandus.com.br

City: Recife | Country: Brazil

Internship:

• I have worked as a game developer using Construct 3 software and JavaScript, building educational games for students from preschool to high school levels.

#### [ 01/06/2021 – 31/10/2021 ] **Game Developer**

**Educandus** https://educandus.com.br

City: Recife | Country: Brazil

Internship:

• I have worked as a game developer using Construct 3 software and JavaScript, building educational games for students from preschool to high school levels.

### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

[ 01/02/2019 - 31/08/2024 ]

# **Bachelor in Computer Engineering**

Federal University of Pernambuco (UFPE) https://portal.cin.ufpe.br

City: Recife | Country: Brazil | Field(s) of study: Information and Communication Technologies: • Software and applications development and analysis • Computer use • Database and network

design and administration • Information and communication technologies not elsewhere classified

• Information and Communication Technologies (ICTs) not further defined; Engineering, manufacturing and construction: • *Electronics and automation* | **Final grade:** 9.02/10.0 | **Level** in EQF: EQF level 6

Link: https://repositorio.ufpe.br/handle/123456789/58235

# [ 01/06/2022 - 31/03/2024 ] **Student Teaching Assistant**

Federal University of Pernambuco (UFPE) https://portal.cin.ufpe.br

Field(s) of study: Information and Communication Technologies: • Software and applications development and analysis

- Dedicated Student Teaching Assistant in the field of Software and Systems Engineering.
- · Provided invaluable support to students in software development and requirements engineering, with a primary goal of crafting top-tier applications of exceptional quality.

# [ 07/11/2024 - 12/11/2024 ] **GraphQL by Example**

Udemy https://udemy.com

Link: https://ude.my/UC-2f72d8c0-5e8c-4c08-a657-cb379948c6f1

# [ 01/11/2024 - 07/11/2024 ] The Complete Cyber Security Course - Volume 1: Hackers Exposed!

Udemy https://udemy.com

Link: https://ude.my/UC-1acdc51c-9652-40d8-80af-24d65aa27727

[ 15/03/2024 - 03/04/2024 ]

# The Complete Flutter Development Bootcamp with Dart

Udemy https://udemy.com

**Link:** https://ude.my/UC-3fd9599a-bff2-4960-8d34-dbb3b41ced55

# [ 01/03/2023 – 14/03/2023 ] Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Data, ML, and AI in Google Cloud - Locales

Google Cloud Skills Boost https://www.cloudskillsboost.google

Link: https://www.cloudskillsboost.google/public\_profiles/d8f54101-4f80-4aee-8e46-2320e3e20646/ badges/3311200?utm\_medium=social&utm\_source=linkedin&utm\_campaign=ql-social-share

[ 01/03/2023 - 13/03/2023 ]

# Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Infrastructure in Google Cloud - Locales

Google Cloud Skills Boost https://www.cloudskillsboost.google

Link: https://www.cloudskillsboost.google/public\_profiles/d8f54101-4f80-4aee-8e46-2320e3e20646/ badges/3303084

[ 01/03/2023 - 13/03/2023 ]

#### **Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Networking**

Google Cloud Skills Boost https://www.cloudskillsboost.google

Link: https://www.cloudskillsboost.google/public\_profiles/d8f54101-4f80-4aee-8e46-2320e3e20646/ badges/3305980

[ 01/03/2023 - 12/03/2023 ]

## Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Cloud Computing Fundamentals - Locales

Google Cloud Skills Boost https://www.cloudskillsboost.google

Link: https://www.cloudskillsboost.google/public\_profiles/d8f54101-4f80-4aee-8e46-2320e3e20646/

badges/3302433

[ 01/04/2020 - 21/04/2020 ]

## The Complete 2020 Web Development Bootcamp

Udemy https://udemy.com

Link: https://ude.my/UC-5d594204-a414-4cb1-a388-72e3daf7c1c6

# **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): Portuguese

Other language(s):

#### **English**

LISTENING C1 READING C2 WRITING C2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

# German

LISTENING A2 READING A2 WRITING A2

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION A2 SPOKEN INTERACTION A2** 

# **DIGITAL SKILLS**

# Digital Skills - Test Results Information and data literacy ADVANCED Level 6 / 6 Communication and collaboration ADVANCED Level 6 / 6 Digital content creation ADVANCED Level 6 / 6 Safety ADVANCED Level 6 / 6 Problem solving ADVANCED Level 6 / 6

Results from <u>self-assessment</u> based on <u>The Digital Competence Framework 2.1</u>

# **HOBBIES AND INTERESTS**

**Games** 

**Reading Books** 

**Travelling** 

Gym

Movies